Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have a lesson that comes actually from a user request.
我是Catherine，今天我们这节课其实是来自一位用户的请求。
That's right.
没错。
We had a user request who asked us if we can do something about a purchasing manager, maybe
有位用户问我们能不能做一期关于采购经理的内容，也许
what his job does or what it is to be a purchasing manager.
讲讲他的工作内容或者采购经理是做什么的。
So you'll find out all about that today in this lesson.
所以今天这节课你会了解到所有相关内容。
It's an upper intermediate about being a purchasing manager and about vendors.
这是一节中高级课程，关于采购经理和供应商。
So let's check out today's dialogue.
那我们来看看今天的对话吧。
Good morning, Angela.
早上好，Angela。
How have you been lately?
你最近怎么样？
Morning Michael.
早上好，Michael。
I've been very busy lately.
我最近一直很忙。
One of our other vendors is going out of business and I've been searching for a suitable replacement.
我们其中一个供应商要倒闭了，我一直在找合适的替代者。
Well rest assured that you can count on us to be here for the long run.
放心吧，你可以信赖我们，我们会长期合作。
Please sit down.
请坐。
Coffee?
喝咖啡吗？
No thanks.
不了，谢谢。
I've been trying to cut down on the caffeine.
我一直在试着减少咖啡因摄入。
I could never do that.
我可做不到。
I'd be a zombie if I didn't have my morning coffee fix.
如果早上不喝杯咖啡提神，我就像个僵尸。
Let's get down to business then.
那我们谈正事吧。
Yes.
好的。
I've come to talk with you about ordering the 8 megapixel cameras for our new MiPhone.
我来是想跟你谈谈为我们新款MiPhone订购800万像素摄像头的事。
The demand for phone cameras is growing and Pear has been falling behind in the market.
手机摄像头的需求在增长，而Pear在市场上已经落后了。
That's great.
太好了。
I'm glad to hear that Pear has finally jumped on the bandwagon.
我很高兴听到Pear终于跟上了潮流。
Right now our contract is for the 5 megapixel cameras.
目前我们的合同是500万像素摄像头。
Is Pear still interested in having those?
Pear还有兴趣要那些吗？
No.
不。
We're changing all the cameras to 8 megapixels.
我们要把所有摄像头换成800万像素。
We were hoping that by making your company our sole supplier for cameras, we could negotiate
我们希望让贵公司成为我们摄像头的独家供应商，这样我们可以协商
a better deal.
一个更好的价格。
Surely.
当然。
Let's get started by drafting a new contract.
我们开始起草一份新合同吧。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a very interesting job to be a purchasing manager.
采购经理这个工作真有意思。
A lot of responsibility on top of him.
他肩上责任很大。
And we actually saw some really interesting phrases and words that are related to business,
我们确实看到了一些非常有趣的短语和词汇，跟商务、
to negotiating, contracts, etc.
谈判、合同等有关。
So let's take a look at some of those now on Language Takeaway.
那我们现在来看看语言要点中的一些内容。
The first word we have is vendor.
第一个词是vendor。
This is a noun.
这是一个名词。
It means it's a job.
它指的是一种职业。
It's the name of a person's job.
是某个人的职业名称。
So he is a vendor.
所以他是个vendor。
And a vendor, what does a vendor do?
那vendor是做什么的？
Well, a vendor sells things.
嗯，vendor是卖东西的人。
So the verb here is to vend, like a vending machine is that machine that you can buy sodas
所以这里的动词是to vend，就像自动售货机（vending machine）是那种你可以买汽水的机器。
from.
So a vendor is someone who sells things to someone else.
所以vendor是把东西卖给其他人的人。
Okay so I can say he is a door vendor.
好的，那我可以说他是个卖门的vendor。
He sells doors?
他卖门？
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
Or let me contact my vendor about the price list for these TVs.
或者让我联系我的vendor，问问这些电视的价格表。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So we're talking about a vendor who is going out of business.
所以我们说的是一个要倒闭的vendor。
And because he's going out of business, this manager is actually looking for a suitable
因为他要倒闭了，这位经理正在找一个合适的
replacement.
替代者。
So this is an interesting phrase because these two words normally go together.
这是一个有趣的短语，因为这两个词通常一起出现。
We say let's find a replacement, okay that's good, but really we want a suitable replacement.
我们说找个替代者，这没问题，但我们真正想要的是合适的替代者。
And so first of all, the word suitable means like appropriate or good.
首先，suitable这个词意思是合适的或好的。
But what about replacement?
那replacement呢？
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
A replacement is something that takes the place of.
Replacement是替代某物的东西。
It replaces something else.
它替换别的东西。
So for example, we have our vendor who went out of business.
比如，我们的vendor倒闭了。
So what we are looking now for is another vendor, but not just any vendor, a suitable
所以我们现在找的是另一个vendor，但不是随便一个，而是合适的
vendor, one that has the things that we need or the prices that we need.
vendor，一个拥有我们需要的东西或价格的。
And in order to replace the one that went out of business.
为了替换那个倒闭的。
Right, so we can say this about other things, not just people.
对，所以我们可以用这个来说其他东西，不只是人。
For example, if I break my iPhone, my cell phone, very expensive phone, I'm upset about
比如，如果我摔坏我的iPhone，我的手机，很贵的手机，我会很郁闷。
it.
But when I buy a new one, I don't want a cheap one.
但当我买新的时，我不想要便宜的。
I want a suitable replacement, one that's about the same as the old one.
我想要一个合适的替代品，跟旧的差不多。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe you don't get the exact same one, but you get one that's very similar.
所以可能不是完全一样的，但非常相似。
Exactly.
正是。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So now they're going to talk a little bit about the contract, but they kind of do a
现在他们要谈一点合同的事，但他们有点
little bit of small talk and they're talking about coffee and he says, well, you know,
他们聊了点闲话，谈到咖啡，他说，嗯，你知道，
I'd be a zombie if I didn't have my morning coffee fix.
如果早上不喝杯咖啡提神，我就像个僵尸一样。
I know how that feels.
我懂那种感觉。
This is a person who loves to drink caffeine to wake up.
这是一个喜欢喝咖啡因来提神的人。
And so we talk about a fix as being something that you need.
所以我们把“fix”说成是你需要的东西。
Okay, my coffee fix means the coffee that I drink in the morning to survive.
好的，我的“coffee fix”指的是我早上为了撑下去而喝的咖啡。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so we know the verb to fix is to make something good again, to repair.
好的，我们知道动词“fix”是让东西变好、修理的意思。
But in this case, we're taking fix as a noun and we're saying that it's something that
但在这里，我们把“fix”当作名词用，指的是你
you need, like you said, for example, maybe in the morning you need your English fix and
需要的东西，就像你说的，比如早上你可能需要你的“English fix”，
so you'd listen to EnglishPod.
所以你会听EnglishPod。
Exactly.
正是。
You need it so much, it's like a drug.
你太需要它了，就像毒品一样。
That's right.
没错。
Very good.
很好。
And moving on, they started to talk a little bit more about the details of the business
接着，他们开始多聊了一些生意的细节，
and he mentioned that they want to make this company their sole supplier for cameras.
他提到他们想让这家公司成为他们唯一的相机供应商。
Okay, so sole means only.
好的，所以“sole”意思是唯一的。
But this word supplier is very interesting because it's very similar to vendor.
但“supplier”这个词很有意思，因为它和“vendor”很相似。
So it's basically someone, a company maybe, or a person that supplies you with what you
所以基本上是指某个人，可能是一家公司，或者一个人，为你提供你
need.
需要的东西。
All right, so to supply is to provide for.
好的，所以“to supply”就是提供。
So for example, if I work at a clothing store and I sell lots of nice clothing, I need a
比如，如果我在一家服装店工作，卖很多漂亮的衣服，我需要一个
supplier to bring me the clothes that I sell.
供应商给我带来我卖的衣服。
Otherwise, where am I going to get them from?
否则，我从哪儿弄来呢？
I don't have a factory.
我又没有工厂。
That's right.
没错。
For example, IBM is one of the biggest computer suppliers or manufacturers in the world.
比如，IBM是世界上最大的电脑供应商或制造商之一。
All right.
好的。
Okay.
嗯。
And for the last part of the dialogue, they said, well, I think we can reach an agreement.
在对话的最后部分，他们说，嗯，我想我们可以达成协议。
Let's get started by drafting a new contract.
让我们开始起草一份新合同吧。
They're going to draft a contract.
他们要起草一份合同。
All right, so this is interesting because we don't use the verb to write a contract.
好的，这很有意思，因为我们不用动词“写”合同。
Now you would think, well, of course you write it, but there's a special verb that we use
你可能会想，当然是你写它，但有一个特殊的动词我们用来
with the word contract.
搭配“合同”这个词。
So just remember this phrase together, to draft a contract or my company will draft
所以只要记住这个短语，“to draft a contract”，或者我的公司会起草
a contract and send it to you.
一份合同并寄给你。
This means to prepare a contract in order for someone to sign it.
这意味着准备一份合同，以便某人签署。
That's right.
没错。
So it's basically the same as write, but it's usually used more with contracts to draft
所以基本上和“写”一样，但通常更多用于合同，“to draft
a contract.
a contract”。
Exactly.
正是。
Or maybe you can say to draft up a business plan.
或者你也可以说“to draft up a business plan”。
Exactly.
正是。
So to draft a plan, to draft a contract.
所以“to draft a plan”，“to draft a contract”。
This is basically to write something that has many different points, many different
这基本上是指写一些有很多不同要点、很多不同
strategies.
策略的东西。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
So five key words for you there.
所以这里有五个关键词。
And now let's move on to some key phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们进入Fluency Builder的一些关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder。
Okay, so there are a lot of really, really juicy phrases in today's lesson.
好的，今天的课程中有很多非常非常精彩的短语。
The first one is rest assured.
第一个是“rest assured”。
So we heard this from Michael at the beginning of the dialogue.
我们在对话开头从Michael那里听到了这个。
He said, rest assured that you can count on us.
他说，“rest assured that you can count on us”。
That's right.
没错。
Rest assured.
“Rest assured”。
So this is a phrase that you use to try to give confidence to someone, telling them you
所以这是一个你用来给别人信心的短语，告诉他们你
can trust me, rest assured that I'll be there.
可以信任我，“rest assured that I'll be there”。
Don't worry.
别担心。
So let's hear another example of it.
让我们再听一个例子。
Rest assured, Marco, I will be there to support you.
“Rest assured, Marco, I will be there to support you.”
Okay, so I know that you will be there or I can trust that you'll be there.
好的，所以我知道你会在那里，或者我可以相信你会在那里。
Okay.
嗯。
Very good.
很好。
So to rest assure.
所以“to rest assure”。
Now the second part of it is in that same sentence, well, rest assure that you can count
现在第二部分是在同一个句子里，“rest assure that you can count
on us.
on us”。
Okay, so what does it mean to count on us, to count on me?
好的，那么“to count on us”、“to count on me”是什么意思？
So the verb to count has a couple of different meanings and most of us are familiar with
所以动词“count”有几个不同的意思，我们大多数人都熟悉
the other one, to count numbers, one, two, three, four, five.
另一个意思，数数，一、二、三、四、五。
But here to count on someone, remember that preposition on, means to expect someone to
但这里的“to count on someone”，记住介词“on”，意思是期望某人
do something, to depend on someone.
做某事，依赖某人。
That's right.
没错。
So if you count on someone, means that you depend on them, you rely on them, you can
所以如果你“count on someone”，意味着你依赖他们，你依靠他们，你可以
trust them.
信任他们。
So for example, in the sentence that I just told Marco, rest assured, I will be there.
比如，在我刚才对Marco说的句子里，“rest assured, I will be there”。
You can count on me.
你可以信赖我。
That means you can depend on me, you can expect me to be there.
这意味着你可以依赖我，你可以期待我在那里。
I will not let you down.
我不会让你失望的。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
In that same sentence, we have another phrasal verb, rest assured that you can count on
在同一句话中，我们还有另一个短语动词，放心，你可以指望
us to be here for the long run.
我们长期在这里。
The long run.
长期。
All right.
好的。
So we're not actually running here.
所以我们实际上不是在这里跑步。
The long run is a phrase that means for a long time.
“长期”是一个短语，意思是长时间。
So for example, if I'm in an interview and someone asks me, well, we're really interested
例如，如果我在面试中，有人问我，嗯，我们真的很感兴趣
in your resume and we really like you.
你的简历，我们真的很喜欢你。
We want to know, are you available in the long run, in the long term?
我们想知道，你长期来看有空吗，长期来说？
That's right.
没错。
So if you say, yes, I am here for the long run, it means that you are here for a long
所以如果你说，是的，我长期在这里，这意味着你在这里待很长
time.
时间。
Okay.
好的。
And let's move on to our next phrase.
让我们继续下一个短语。
And they're actually, you know, they stopped with a small talk and now they want to get
他们实际上，你知道，停止了闲聊，现在他们想
down to business.
开始谈正事。
You hear this phrase all the time because you don't just walk into a meeting and start
你经常听到这个短语，因为你不会直接走进会议室就开始
talking about business stuff.
谈论业务。
You know, you start with the nice things first.
你知道，你先说些好听的。
You say, how was your weekend?
你说，你周末过得怎么样？
How is your wife?
你妻子怎么样？
How was that game of golf?
那场高尔夫球赛怎么样？
So you're talking about nice small talk, like you just said, Marco, but when you want to
所以你在聊愉快的闲聊，就像你刚才说的，Marco，但当你想
start talking about numbers or products, things like that, that is called business.
开始谈论数字或产品之类的东西时，那才叫业务。
So when you want to start that, you say, let's get down to business.
所以当你想开始时，你说，让我们开始谈正事吧。
That's right.
没错。
So it's a phrase to say, okay, now let's start talking about what we came here to do.
所以这是一个短语，意思是，好了，现在让我们开始谈论我们来这里要做的事。
Start talking about business.
开始谈论业务。
And the last phrase that we have for you, it's a very interesting phrase.
我们为你准备的最后一个短语，是一个非常有趣的短语。
When they were talking about one of the brands of phones, they're saying, I'm glad to hear
当他们谈论其中一个手机品牌时，他们说，我很高兴听到
that Pear has finally jumped on the bandwagon.
Pear 终于跟风了。
Now, Marco, I wish I could tell you, I knew where this phrase came from, but I don't.
现在，Marco，我希望我能告诉你我知道这个短语的来历，但我不知道。
Let's just talk about the word bandwagon first.
我们先谈谈“bandwagon”这个词。
I think bandwagon means something that everyone is doing.
我认为“bandwagon”的意思是大家都在做的事情。
That's right.
没错。
So I think if everyone likes the color purple and all of a sudden you like the color purple,
所以我认为如果每个人都喜欢紫色，然后突然你也喜欢紫色，
then that means you just jumped on the bandwagon.
那就意味着你只是跟风了。
All right.
好的。
I jumped on the bandwagon.
我跟风了。
So you think of a wagon as like, before they had cars, they had wagons.
所以你可以把 wagon 想象成，在汽车出现之前，他们有马车。
They're wooden and they have wheels and they're pulled by a horse.
它们是木制的，有轮子，由马拉着。
And so everyone is on there and they're all going somewhere.
所以每个人都在上面，他们都去某个地方。
And I wasn't on it, but I jumped on the back.
而我本来不在上面，但我跳上了后面。
That means I joined everyone.
这意味着我加入了大家。
I started to do what they're doing.
我开始做他们正在做的事。
That's right.
没错。
So I guess you agree with them or you're going towards in the same direction that everyone
所以我猜你同意他们，或者你朝着大家
else is going.
去的同一个方向前进。
Look at Marco.
看看 Marco。
He just bought an iPhone.
他刚买了一部 iPhone。
Now he's jumped on the bandwagon.
现在他跟风了。
That's right.
没错。
So everyone is going in the same direction.
所以每个人都朝着同一个方向前进。
Everyone is doing the same thing.
每个人都在做同样的事。
Everyone likes the same thing.
每个人都喜欢同样的东西。
So to jump on the bandwagon, you can use it in the business sense.
所以“跟风”这个词，你可以在商业意义上使用它。
For example, if somebody is not agreeing with you or somebody doesn't want to support your
例如，如果有人不同意你，或者有人不想支持你的
project, you can say, I would really appreciate it if you jumped on the bandwagon and supported
项目，你可以说，如果你能跟风支持我们
us on this.
这个项目，我会非常感激。
That's right.
没错。
So it's not always a bad thing, but remember that the verb that is synonymous with this
所以这不总是坏事，但记住，与这个同义的动词
is to conform.
是“顺从”。
Okay.
好的。
To do what everyone else is doing.
做别人都在做的事。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of interesting things here.
所以这里有很多有趣的东西。
Let's listen to our dialogue one last time.
让我们最后听一遍我们的对话。
Good morning, Angela.
早上好，Angela。
How have you been lately?
你最近怎么样？
Morning Michael.
早上好，Michael。
I've been very busy lately.
我最近很忙。
One of our other vendors is going out of business and I've been searching for a suitable replacement.
我们其中一个供应商要倒闭了，我一直在寻找合适的替代者。
Well rest assured that you can count on us to be here for the long run.
嗯，放心，你可以指望我们长期在这里。
Please sit down.
请坐。
Coffee?
喝咖啡吗？
No, thanks.
不了，谢谢。
I've been trying to cut down on the caffeine.
我一直在努力减少咖啡因的摄入。
I could never do that.
我可做不到。
I'd be a zombie if I didn't have my morning coffee fix.
早上不喝杯咖啡提神，我就像个僵尸。
Let's get down to business then.
那我们直接谈正事吧。
Yes.
好的。
I've come to talk with you about ordering the eight megapixel cameras for our new Mi
我来是想跟你谈谈为我们的新Mi
phone.
手机订购八百万像素摄像头的事。
The demand for phone cameras is growing and Pear has been falling behind in the market.
手机摄像头的需求在增长，而Pear在市场上已经落后了。
That's great.
太好了。
I'm glad to hear that Pear has finally jumped on the bandwagon.
很高兴听到Pear终于跟上了潮流。
Right now our contract is for the five megapixel cameras.
目前我们的合同是五百万像素摄像头。
Is Pear still interested in having those?
Pear还有兴趣要那些吗？
No.
不。
We're changing all the cameras to eight megapixels.
我们正在把所有摄像头换成八百万像素的。
We were hoping that by making your company our sole supplier for cameras, we could negotiate
我们希望通过让贵公司成为我们摄像头的独家供应商，来协商
a better deal.
一个更好的价格。
Surely.
当然。
Let's get started by drafting a new contract.
我们开始起草一份新合同吧。
So talking about purchasing, it's actually a very interesting position.
说到采购，这其实是一个非常有趣的职位。
I think many, or almost all companies, big companies have this position where not only
我认为很多，或者说几乎所有公司，大公司都有这个职位，不仅
do they have to, maybe if they're in retailing, they have to purchase the goods that they
是零售业需要采购要卖的商品，
will sell, but also in offices.
办公室也需要。
For example, who buys the paper, the printers, the copiers, everything for the office?
比如，谁买纸、打印机、复印机，以及办公室的一切用品？
That's right.
没错。
This is a very important position, as you say, because this person can save a company
正如你所说，这是一个非常重要的职位，因为如果这个人了解合适的供应商，
a lot of money if the person knows the right vendors.
就能为公司省下很多钱。
That's right.
没错。
If the only vendors you know are selling things at very high prices, then that's not very
如果你只知道那些卖高价东西的供应商，那对你或你的生意
good for you or for your business.
都不太好。
But if you know all the inside secrets, you know all the good vendors, then maybe you're
但如果你知道所有内部秘诀，了解所有好供应商，那你可能
going to be able to save a lot of money.
就能省下很多钱。
That's right.
没错。
I think this position is also a lot broader than just this.
我认为这个职位比这还要广泛得多。
Maybe someone can also help us out on the website, EnglishPod.com.
也许有人也能在我们的网站EnglishPod.com上帮帮忙。
You can explain.
你可以解释一下。
Maybe if you're a purchasing manager, you can tell us what your job entails.
如果你是个采购经理，你可以告诉我们你的工作内容是什么。
Or if you know a purchasing manager, what does that person do?
或者如果你认识一个采购经理，那个人是做什么的？
That's right.
没错。
We're very curious to know, and we hope that you'll be able to use some of these new words
我们很好奇，也希望你能用上这些新词
and phrases.
和短语。
If you want to practice, check us out, EnglishPod.com.
如果你想练习，就来我们的网站EnglishPod.com看看吧。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们那儿见。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Robert Fukunaga, EnglishPod number two, EnglishPod number two.
Robert Fukunaga，EnglishPod第二期，EnglishPod第二期。